Michelle Kirkland

FRONT END SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Dallas, TX • <u>michelle.rf.kirkland@gmail.com</u> • 972.768.6457 <u>Portfolio</u> • <u>GitHub</u> • <u>LinkedIn</u>

SUMMARY

Front end developer with over 10 years' website building and graphic design experience. Highly motivated, creative, and an excellent communicator. Excited to contribute a diverse skill set to a company dedicated to making an impact.

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Typescript • React.js, Material UI • Node.js, Express, MongoDB, AWS, GitHub Tailwind, Sass, WordPress, PHP • RESTful APIs • Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Figma, Canva

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, 100Devs — Los Angeles, CA (remote)

SEPTEMBER 2022 - PRESENT

- Collaborates with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications using best practices
- Builds semantically structured full stack web applications with React and other technologies
- Applies agile methodologies like SCRUM for project management

Website Content Manager, 48in48 — Atlanta, GA (remote)

APRIL 2024

- Collaborates with UX/UI and other developers to create keyword-rich content that achieves site goals
- Applies technical writing skill and accessibility expertise to ensure appropriate content creation

Photographer, Michelle Kirkland Photography — *Dallas, TX*

2015 - 2022

- Built & managed Wordpress website, digital marketing, and publishing with Adobe Creative Suite
- Applied advanced editing techniques to produce high-quality photographs
- Collaborated closely with clients while significantly increasing average sale from \$200 to \$2,500

Bilingual Music Teacher, Irving ISD — *Irving, TX*

2004 - 2015

- Sourced and delivered innovative instruction to K-8 music students
- Wrote grant proposal that secured iPads for the music classroom
- Assisted colleagues and IT staff with software and equipment installation

AWARDS

Hackathon Winner — Awarded by Girl Develop It for app connecting BIPOC patients with health providers (2022)

Fulbright Scholar — Awarded by the University of Texas (2006)

EDUCATION

Master's Degree — University of North Texas • **Bachelor's Degree** — University of the Pacific